In writing queries, one will sometimes need to
join several tables to get a filter on two fields.
This process can get expensive on resources,
so one alternative is to use a subquery,
a SELECT statement inside of a SELECT statement,
and keywords used to meet certain needs. Here
is one example. I want to show product
names for any product that sold at least
ten units within a detailed order. Thus,
I have a query set to show the ProductID
and the Name from the Production.Product
table, and the criteria I want are located
in the Sales.SalesOrderDetail table. However, I
don't need to display any fields from that table,
which is the key to using a subquery. If you
don't need to display any fields from a table
you would otherwise join, a subquery
may be faster. Before I execute this,
let's step through this WHERE clause. This
clause states where Product ID equals ANY
ProductID from the Sales.SalesOrderDetail table
where the orderqty >= 10. In executing this, about
136 products have had an order quantity of at
least ten. The ANY keyword represents this:
If there is at least one match in the subquery,
those records will display in the result set.